William Gropper Papers
William Gropper Papers
1918-1981
1943-1944
Gropper, William, 1897-1977.
8 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter, illustrator, cartoonist, lithographer. Correspondence (1927-1950); original drawings, paintings, and prose by Gropper and others; published material, including cartoons from New Masses, clippings, exhibition lists, and illustrations (1918-1968); and a scrapbook containing birthday congratulations.
149022
Biographical History
William Gropper (1897-1977) was an American born Jewish cartoonist, painter, lithographer, and muralist. Born in New York City on the lower East side where his parents worked in the garment industry, he attended the Ferrer School and the New York School of Fine and Applied Arts and began exhibiting his paintings in the 1930's. As a cartoonist he worked for the Daily Worker, Morning Freiheit, New Masses, New York Tribune, and several other mainstream and leftist publications. Gropper was known not only for his depiction of social injustice as it played out in the day-to-day life of the common laborer, but also through his satirical portrayal of the elite and powerful and the effects of capitalism and war on American life.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Gropper Papers, spanning 1918-1970 (bulk 1942-1944), comprises correspondence, artwork, writings, and memorabilia of the artist.
The mostly incoming Correspondence consists primarily of notes and letters presented to Gropper at the 1944 birthday celebration given in his honor. The Birthday Scrapbook was compiled by Gropper's friends and fellow artists, and Edward K. Barsky, M.D., Chairman of the Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, in honor of Gropper's 47th birthday. The dinner celebration was hosted by screenwriter and producer Edward Chodorov (opening remarks are included). Speakers included Carl Sandburg, Frederick Myers, and Norman Corwin with tributes by Dean Dixon, Dorothy Parker, Henry Varnum Poor, Captain Orest Shevsov, and Margaret Lombardo Toledano. Sponsors included Leonard Bernstein, Van Wyck Brooks, Marc Chagall, Aaron Copland, Louis Lozowick, W. Somerset Maugham, Anton Refregier, Louis Slobodkin, Moses Soyer, and Margaret Webster, among others. Cards, letters, telegrams, signatures, and artwork from Ella Reeve "Mother" Bloor, Earl Browder, Carreño, Theodore Dreiser, Howard Fast, Joseph Hirsch, Langston Hughes, Harold Ickes, Rockwell Kent, the Kukryniksy artists, Luis Quintanilla, Paul Robeson, Bodo Uhse, and Max Yergan are included. Labor unions, artist and political associations, and newspapers are also represented.
Correspondence from various U.S. government departments and offices include: the U.S. Coordinator of Information, inviting Gropper to contribute cartoons that will be sent abroad for propaganda purposes; the U.S. Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs regarding a pamphlet on Lidice, Czechoslovakia; the U.S. Federal Works Agency in connection with Gropper's Lidice drawings and exhibitions of Gropper's artwork; the U.S. Office of War Information regarding government war posters, the Lidice book(let), and a memo to Archibald MacLeish, Director of the Office's Office of Facts and Figures, about a meeting of artists MacLeish called to discuss how they might contribute to the war effort; and the U.S. Treasury Department concerning war bond posters, an exhibition on war cartoons, the Lidice drawings, and a trip to visit the Parker and Grand Coulee dams in preparation for his mural in the U.S. Department of Interior building.
Some of the items have been removed from the scrapbook for conservation purposes and placed in the correspondence file folders. The details and an index to all correspondence are given at the end of this finding aid.
Artwork includes original and reproductions of cartoons, drawings, etchings, and sketches for publications such as Freiheit and the New Masses. Mediums include charcoal, pastel, pen and ink, and pencil. Printed materials, such as a calendar and other publications Gropper illustrated, are also included, along with clippings of published artwork appearing in journals and newspapers.
Writings include an outline of Gropper's life and handwritten statements and comments regarding his testimony before Senator Joseph McCarthy's House Un-American Committee in 1953.
Memorabilia comprises an award from the U.S. Treasury Department for services rendered on behalf of the National War Savings program; book reviews and publicity for Gropper's book, Alay-Oop; cartoons by J. Sennep (Jean Pennes); exhibition materials such as announcements and invitations, catalogs, and publicity and reviews; financial and legal material encompassing a voucher from the U.S. Treasury Department for the materials, painting, and installation of the mural in the Department of Interior building; from the U.S. Office of Emergency Management for illustrations included in a booklet on the Lidice (Czechoslovakia) massacre, sketches for war-themed posters depicting Hitler and Mussolini; a contract with the Philosophical Library to provide illustrations and a jacket drawing for Shaw's Crime of Punishment (Crime of Imprisonment); publicity (general) including New Masses and Art Editions ads for Gropper's lithographs and a New Currents ad for a reproduction; sketches of Gropper drawn by others; theater programs (in Russian); and writings by others (two poems by Gladys Oaks). Miscellaneous items include football and concert programs (in Russian), the constitution and by-laws of the American Artists' Congress, invitations, award committee lists, the 1944 birthday program, stationery, lists, handwritten notes, and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Refer to the index to correspondence at the end of this inventory for a detailed list. Artworks is subdivided into originals and reproductions, and within that arranged alphabetically by media. Printed material is arranged alphabetically by type of materialand within that alphabetically by title of the publication. Writings are also arranged alphabetically by title, while Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by form of material (e.g., exhibit catalogs).
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Art -- Illustrators; Radicalism; Gropper, William, 1897-1977.; New masses.; Art -- Political aspects.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Heroes -- Folklore -- Pictorial works.; Illustrators -- United States.; Lithographers -- United States.; Painters, United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Articles.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Exhibition catalogs.; Illustrations.; Paintings (visual works); Photographs.; Programs (documents); Scrapbooks.; Artists.; Cartoonists.; Illustrators.; Lithographers.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William Gropper, 1964, 1969.
Framed item, gift of Bert Boyson, 2010.
Original pen and ink sketch, purchased 2013.
Lithographs of American folk heroes and personal photographs, gift of Dawna (Gropper) Snyder, 2014.
Headless horseman lithograph, purchased 2005.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
    See also Memorabilia for additional material about Gropper and his artwork.
- Correspondence files
  - A-Z, circa 1931-1951; bulk 1942-1944; 31 folders (Box 1)
    See also Birthday scrapbook for additional correspondence
  - Unidentified (Box 1)
  - Greeting cards from Groppers, with Gropper's artwork (Box 1)
- Artwork
  - Originals
    - Charcoal drawings (Box 2)
    - Etchings (Box 2)
    - Oil and wash/watercolor paintings, includes negatives for reproductions (Box 2)
    - Lithographs, American folk heroes, Paul Bunyan, Davy Crockett, etc.; 8 items (Oversize 1)
      Gift of Dawna (Gropper) Snyder, 2014.
    - Pastel drawing (Box 2)
    - Pen and ink drawings, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Pen and ink drawing, 9-panel illustration on wage slavery; note on back suggests it may have been for the Soviet magazine Krokodil (Oversize 9)
      Purchased 2013.
    - Pencil drawings (Box 2)
    - Sketches (Box 2)
  - Reproductions
    - Linoleum cut (Box 2)
    - Pen and ink drawings (Box 2)
    - Photograph of a painting (Box 2)
    - Photograph of a sculpture (Box 2)
    - Photographs of pen and ink drawings, includes negatives; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Artwork - printed material
  - Advertisements
    - Invitation to "Playboys' Plantation Strut and Mississippi Steamboat Jubilee" (Playboy: A Portfolio of Art and Satire) (Oversize 9)
    - War bonds (Oversize 1)
  - Books
    - Alay-Oop, book jacket, front cover (Oversize 1)
    - Down There (La Bas) by J.K. Huysmans, illustrated by Gropper; book jacket (Oversize 1)
    - Whither, Whither, or, After Sex What? by Walter S. Hankel, illustrated by Gropper; book spine (Oversize 1)
  - Calendars
    - Russian War Relief Inc., Sep 1942 (Oversize 1)
    - "Victory 1942, a Calendar and Sixteen Prints for Democracy" (United American Artists) (Oversize 1)
  - Clippings
    - Journals
      - The American Commentator, Oct 1934; undated (Oversize 2)
      - Arts & Decorations, Mar 1923 (Oversize 2)
      - The Bookman, undated (Oversize 2)
      - The Fight for Peace and Democracy, Feb 1938; Mar 1939 (Oversize 2)
      - Folio, 10 Feb 1924; undated (Oversize 2)
      - Judge, 6 Apr 1929 (Oversize 2)
      - KEN, 7 Apr 1938 (Oversize 2)
      - The Liberator, Jan 1919 (Oversize 2)
      - The Literary Review, 28 Oct 1922 (Oversize 2)
      - Look, 12 Apr 1938 (Oversize 2)
      - The Medical Quip, undated (Oversize 2)
      - Motion Picture Magazine, undated (Oversize 2)
      - The Nation, circa 1932-1947 (Oversize 2)
      - The National Financial News, Jun-Jul 1923 (Oversize 2)
      - New Masses, 1927-1946; 12 folders (Oversize 3)
      - The New Pearson's, Feb 1923; Jun 1923,; Jul 1923 (Oversize 2)
      - The New Republic, circa 1947-1948 (Oversize 2)
      - PIC, May 1948 (Oversize 2)
      - Playboy: A Portfolio of Art and Satire (New York), undated (Oversize 2)
      - Shadowland, undated (Oversize 2)
      - Tennis, Jun 1931 (Oversize 2)
      - Vanity Fair, May 1934; Aug 1935,; undated (Oversize 2)
      - Vogue, 1 Apr 1934 (Oversize 2)
      - The Working Front, undated (Oversize 2)
      - The Younger Set, Feb 1924 (Oversize 2)
      - Unidentified, 1948; undated; 4 folders (Oversize 2)
    - Newspapers
      - The Advance, circa 1922-1923 (Oversize 4)
      - The Capital Times, 11 Feb 1940 (Oversize 4)
      - Daily News, 2 Nov 1942 (Oversize 4)
      - Daily Worker, 1927-1947; undated; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Fur & Leather Worker, Aug 1944 (Oversize 4)
      - New York American, 1934; undated; includes Robert Benchley columns; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - New York Evening Graphic Magazine, Aug-Sep 1929 (Oversize 4)
      - New York Evening Post Literary Review, 1924; undated; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - New York Times Book Review, circa 1931-1947 (Oversize 4)
      - New York Tribune, 1918-1919 (Oversize 5)
      - New York Herald Tribune Books, 14 Sep 1930; 2 folders (Oversize 5)
      - The New York World, 1925-1926; undated; 2 folders (Oversize 5)
      - PM's Weekly, 24 Aug 1941; Sep 1941 (Oversize 5)
      - The San Francisco News, 20 Feb 1937 (Oversize 5)
      - Sunday Worker, 1939-1940 (Oversize 5)
      - The Young Worker, 3 Dec 1927 (Oversize 5)
      - Ring Lardner columns, circa 1926 (Oversize 5)
      - Unidentified, 1924; undated; 5 folders (Oversize 5)
    - Newspapers and journals
      - Clippings from scrapbook, disassembled (Oversize 5)
    - Newspapers, foreign language
      - Czechoslovakian (tvorba), 1948 (Oversize 6)
      - French, 1930; undated (Oversize 6)
        See also Memorabilia: Cartoons by J. Sennep (Jean Pennes)
      - German, circa 1920-1928; undated (Oversize 6)
      - Polish, 1950; undated (Oversize 6)
      - Russian, circa 1927-1938; undated; 3 folders (Oversize 6)
      - Spanish, 1938; undated (Oversize 6)
      - Yiddish (Morning Freiheit), circa 1924-1948; undated (Box 3)
      - Yiddish (Morning Freiheit), circa 1924-1948; undated; oversize items (Oversize 7)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Framed piece with three Gropper items, 1971; 1930; anti-racism first day cover with Gropper cartoon, signed, and a Gropper illustration from Pionier-Kalendar; also a small candid photo of Gropper (Oversize 9)
        This item gift of Bert Boyson, 2010
      - Portraits of American Ecclesiastics, undated (Box 3)
  - Cover art (journals)
    - The American Stockholder, Sep 1934 (Oversize 1)
    - Caravan, Sep 1945 (Oversize 1)
    - China Today, Dec 1934 (Oversize 1)
    - Direction, Jan 1940 (Oversize 1)
    - Echo: The Rocky Mountain Magazine, Apr 1927 (Oversize 1)
    - The Fight for Peace and Democracy, Mar 1935; Nov 1936 (Oversize 1)
    - Der Hammer (Yiddish), Oct 1926; Aug 1927,; Feb 1934,; Mar 1934,; Oct 1934 (Oversize 1)
    - The Liberator, Aug 1922 (Oversize 1)
    - Magazine of Art, Aug 1937 (Oversize 1)
    - New World Review, Nov 1951 (Oversize 1)
    - Pagan, May 1921 (Oversize 1)
    - The Revolutionary Age, Jul 26, 1919 (Oversize 1)
    - TAC (Theatre Arts Committee), Jul 1938 (Oversize 1)
    - What's New mailing envelope, undated (Oversize 1)
      See also Artwork - Printed material: Clippings: Journals: New Masses.
  - Pamphlets
    - "In Gold We Trust" by Larry Harr, illustrated by Gropper (Oversize 1)
    - "The Last Mile", playbill cover illustrated by Gropper (Oversize 1)
    - "A Noon-Hour Talk on the Communist Party" by Harrison George, illustrated by Gropper (Oversize 1)
    - "12 Cartoons Defending WPA", American Artists' Congress (Oversize 1)
    - "12 Etchings", foreword by Alan Fern (Oversize 1)
    - "Unity", in Polish, illustrated by Gropper (Oversize 1)
  - Prints
    - Headless horseman (Oversize 9)
      Purchase, 2005.
    - Shtetl (Oversize 9)
    - Shtetl (Oversize 10)
- Writings
  - Manuscripts
    - "Anyone who thinks a witness gets a fair hearing at the hands of McCarthy..." (Box 3)
    - Gropper's life, outline (Box 3)
    - Paul Bunyan (Box 3)
    - Statement of William Gropper [before HUAC], 6 May 1953 (Box 3)
    - "When an American Artist whose work is in the permanent collections of the most important museums throughout the country...", re: Sen. McCarthy and the House Un-American Committee (HUAC) (Box 3)
- Memorabilia
  - Articles about Gropper, 1930-1963; undated; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Articles about Gropper, Aug 1935; undated; re: Gropper's depiction of Emperor Hirohito in Vanity Fair; 6 folders (Box 3)
    See also Artwork - Printed material: Clippings: Journals: Vanity Fair
  - Award, 27 May 1942; U.S. Treasury Department (Box 4)
  - Book reviews and publicity for Alay-Oop, circa 1930-1931; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Cartoons by J. Sennep (Jean Pennes), circa 1935; in French (Box 4)
  - Exhibition announcements and invitations, circa 1950-1970 (Box 4)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1921-1971; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Exhibition publicity and reviews, circa 1930-1957 (Box 4)
  - Financial and legal material, circa 1938-1945 (Box 4)
  - Photographs, personal, 1964; 1981 (Box 4)
  - Publicity, general, circa 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Sketches of Gropper drawn by others, circa 1949 (Box 4)
  - Theater programs (in Russian), circa 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - Writings by others, undated; poems by Gladys Oaks (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1927-1950; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Birthday scrapbook, inscribed "To Bill Gropper from his friends December 4, 1944" (Oversize 8)
Index to correspondence
All correspondence contained in the Gropper Papers is filed alphabetically under Correspondence or contained in the birthday scrapbook. Loose correspondence from the scrapbook was removed and filed alphabetically under Correspondence. These items are so noted in the index and the scrapbook, and on the back of the correspondence item. Some signatures were difficult to read. Partially readable names are indexed and include a "?" while unreadable names are indexed under the heading "unidentified correspondence/signatures."
Page numbers are designated "B1" for correspondence filed in Box 1 or "S" followed by the page number for correspondence found in the scrapbook (page numbers have been assigned and are not original). Bold "S" numbers indicate a drawing is included while italicized numbers indicate signatures only. For loose correspondence removed from the scrapbook and added to Box 1, the designation "B1" appears first, followed by the "S" number in parentheses, to indicate original placement.
Abrams, Harry M. S48
Abrams, Nina S48
Abromowitz, Ben S41
Abusch, Alexander S20
Adamic, LouisS8 (program) S31
Addis, Dr. Thomas S11
Adlow, Dorothy S50
Albany Print Club B1
American Artists Group, Inc. (New York) B1
American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (New York) B1 (S47)
American Communications Association, CIO (St. Louis) B1 (S55)
American Fraternal Society S68
American Labor Party (New York) B1 (S33)
Amter, Israel S6
Anderson, Margaret? B1 (S35)
Apresian, Stephan S38
Arnold, August S62
Arons, George B1 (S56)
Art Institute of ChicagoB1 S6
Art Supplies for Russia (San Francisco) S61
Associated American Artists, Inc. (New York) S62
Auslander, Dr. Jacob B. B1 (S49) S40
Auslander, Mrs. J. S40
Bachrach, Marion S63
Baer, Howard S40
Baker, Fannie B1 (S71)
Baker, Fran S36
Baker, Jacob See Vanguard Press
Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America (New York) S64
Balaban, Josephine S34
Ball, Archey D. See Methodist Church, (Leonia, NJ)
Balokovic, Zlato S8 (program)
Banning, Margaret Culkin B1 (S43)
Barasch, Sylvia S36
Barbusse, Henri B1
Barlow, S.L.M S8 (program)
Barnett, Fannie S46
Barron, Samuel. See The Daily Worker (New York)
Barsky, Edward K. S10 (program)
Bass, Charlotta A. See The California Eagle (Los Angeles)
Bassow, Mary S32
Bassow, Sam S32
Bayer, Flo S28
Bayer, Theodore S42
Beach, Sara Brown S34
Bedacht, Elizabeth S34
Bedacht, MaxS8 (program) S34
Beim, Jerold S28
Beim, Lorraine S28
Beinberg, Sarah S48
Beloff, David S48
Beloff, Sonia S48
Bennett, Richard Dyer S10 (program)
Benson, Arthur S62
Bergman, Bernard S62
Bergman, Ruth L. S26
Berkowitz, Sylvia S28
Bernstein, Leonard S8 (program)
Bert, Erik S42
Bessie, Alvah B1 (S58)
Beube, Edith D.B1 (S35) S30
Beube, Frank E.B1 (S35) S30
Beuhenwald, N. S30
Beuhenwald, Stella S30
Biberman, Edward B1 (S56)
Biddle, George See U.S. War Department
Bidner, William R. See National CIO War Relief Committee (Los Angeles)
Biggs, George. See U.S. War Department
Bittleware, Eva S50
Black, Helen S48
Blitzstein, Maddie S60
Blitzstein, Sam S60
Bloch, Harry M.D. S46
Block, Jack S28
Block, Lota ? S28
Bloor, Ella Reeve "Mother," S60 S65
Blossom, Frederick A. B1 (S24)
Blume Peter S8 (program)
Borchardt, Mr. and Mrs. A.E. S71
Borden, Sidney S3
Boulder Eagle S26
Boutte, Oliver S68
Bowman, Franklin S40
Boyd, Helen S60
Bradley, Chester D. M.D. B1 (S29)
Bradley, Francine S61
Bradley, Lyman R. S61
Brandl, John B1 (S19)
Brandon, Delphine B1 (S45)
Bravetell, Louise B1 (S50)
Brechsbee, Dr. William S47
Brewer, Joseph S26
Bridges, Harry S36
Brigadier, Anne S40
Brigadier, Maurice C. ? S40
Brigman, Mrs. B. B1 (S65)
Brodin, Greta S26
Brook, AlexanderS8 (program) S48
Brooks, Van Wyck S8 (program)
Browder, Earl S33
Browder, W. E. See The Daily Worker (New York)
Brown, Adele S. See U.S. Federal Works Agency
Brown, Blanche. See Metropolitan Museum of Art
Brown, Milton W. See Metropolitan Museum of Art
Brumer, Abe S36
Bryan, Alice Reid (Mrs. W.S. Plumer) B1 (S45)
Bryan, Helen R. S3
Buckler, Leslie H. See University of Virginia
Buckmaster, Henrietta S8 (program)
Budenz, Louis F. S42
Burger, Rev. Fred William S72
Burt, Ethel S38
Burt, SamS38 S59
Cacchione, Peter V. S6
Calder, Alexander S8 (program)
The California Eagle (Los Angeles) B1 (S53)
Candela, Louis S68
Carmier?, Theresa B1 (S35)
Carnegie Hall S42
Carnegie Institute B1
Carrell, Theodora M. S66
Carreño S5
Carter, Edward C. See Russian War Relief, Inc. (New York)
Case, Kenneth T. See U.S. War Department
Cervantes Fraternal Society, IWO (New York) S39
Chagall, Marc S8 (program)
Chamberlain, Lowell. See The Pilot (National Maritime Union of America, CIO)
Chamberlain, Miriam S36
Chamberlain, Thomas S36
Chase, Allan S8 (program)
Chatham Music School S26
Chatham Pharmacy (Lynn, MA) B1 (S45)
Chattanooga Times B1
Chefs, Cooks, Pastry Cooks and Assistants Union of New York B1 (S51)
Cheremenykh, Mikhail S9
Chertak, Dorothy S50
Chodorov, EdwardS4 (opening remarks) S7 (program) S8 (program) S10 (program)
Chodorov, Jerry B1 (S24)
Chodorov, Midge S3
Christensen, Thomas S63
The Christian Register B1 (S25)
Cimbalo, Michael B1
Cirkovsky, Nicolai S30
Cleveland, Colby S48
Club Obreo Español, Inc. (New York) S68
Coffee, John M. (Cong.) See U.S. Congress
Cohen, Louis S65
Colgate-Rochester Divinity School (Roch., NY) B1 (S47)
Colin, Charles H. S30
Collins, Charles A.S30 S64
Collins, Veola N. S30
Colloms, Lionel See United Federal Workers of America, CIO
Colman, Louis S30
Colon, Jesus S39
Colvin, Berris D. S30
Colvin, Charles H. B1 (S25)
Committee Pro Democracia Española S68
Communist Political Association (New York)S6 S33
Connelly, Philip M. See Los Angeles City Council
Connolly, Eugene P. See American Labor Party (New York)
Conrad, Mabel See American Labor Party (New York); Washington Pension Union (Seattle)
Consul General of Mexico in New York S14
Cope, Eliza M. (Mrs. Walker)B1 (S50) S50
Copland, Aaron S8 (program)
Corretjer, Juan Antonio See The Daily Worker (New York)
Corwin, NormanS7 (program) S8 (program) S10 (program)
Costrell, H.J. S30
Council for Pan American Democracy (New York) S63
Covarrubias, Miquel S20
Cowan, Leo See Chatham Pharmacy (Lynn, MA)
Cox, Edwin See Kenyon & Eckhardt, Inc. (advertising)
Coy, Wayne See White House: Roosevelt Administration
Cramer, Marie B1, (S24)
Crawford, Rev. Horatio H. S72
Croation Benevolent Fraternity of America, IWO B1 (S18)
Cuesta, FabriS3 S11 S20
Cunningham, Dorothy S36
Cunningham, E.J. S36
Czechoslovak Information Service (New York) B1
Daigel, Louis See Furniture Workers Union, CIO (New York)
The Daily Worker (New York)B1 (S23) B1 (S24) B1 (S52) S42
Davidson, Jo S8 (program)
Davis, Benjamin, J. Jr. S72
Davis, Effie L. (Mrs. W.G.) S71
Davis, Horace B. S70
Davis, Lena S28
Davis, S.K. See Minnesota Labor (Minneapolis)
De Maio, Ernst S23
Deak, Zoltan See Magyar Jövö (Hungarian daily journal)
DeCicco, Michael See Furniture Workers Union, CIO (New York)
Dehn, Adolf S8 (program)
DeKoren, Renee S62
DeLacey, Hugh S39
DeLacey for Congress (Seattle) S39
deLappe, Pele (and Vicky ?) S61
Delehanty, John M. See U.S. Treasury Department
DeMaio, Ernest See United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America, CIO
Denisovsky, N.F. S9
Dennis, Eugene S33
Desmond, R. J. See U.S. War Department
Detwiller, Frederick K. S42
Deutsch, Babette S40
Deutsh, Helen See Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (Culver City, CA)
Diamant, Rose B.S38 S70
DiBiase, Adelina S34
DiBiase, Joseph S34
Dicks, Evelyn B1 (S19)
D'Inzillo, Mario S68
Dirkss, John S26
Dixon, DeanS7 (program) S8 (program) S10 (program)
Dodson, Luelith W. S65
Douglas, Helen Gahagan Gahagan, Helen
Dowbak, Peter See Furniture Workers Union, CIO (New York)
Downie, Douglas S26
Dows, Olin See U.S. Federal Works Agency; U.S. Treasury Department
Draper, Paul S8 (program)
Dreiser, Theodore S60
Drosier, Juliet S28
Drury, James See National Maritime Union of America, CIO (New York)
Duboff, Elizabeth E. S6